

# Victor Fernando Lopes de Souza

Engineering Student at CentraleSupélec

8 July 1999, Brazilian

+33 0665923179

victorfer.lopsouza@student-cs.fr

in linkedin.com/in/victorflosouza

github.com/victorsouza89

# About Me —

Passionate for innovation and technology. Interested in approaching complex problems and grasping complex concepts.

Looking for a final year internship starting in May 2023.

Enthusiast of Mathematics, System Modeling, Control Systems and Temporal Logic.

# Skills -

Good Mathematical Background and knowledge in Control's Systems, Automata and Discrete-Event's Systems.

Multiple experiences on Python, LETEX, Matlab, Simulink, Linux, Git, R, Ladder, Java, C++, AutoIt and BASIC.

Experience on data analysis and neural nets using Pandas, Numpy, Tensforflow and Keras.

Experience on Web developing using PHP, HTML, CSS, SQL and JavaScript.

Languages: Portuguese (mother tongue), English, French and Spanish.

#### Education

2022-2023	Université Paris-Saclay Master in Systems, Signals and Image Processing	Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR)
2021-2023	CentraleSupélec Engineering, with mention in Control	Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR)
2018-2023	UFSC - Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina Control and Automation Engineering PAM - Advanced Mathematics Program	Florianópolis (BR)
2021-2022	Paris IV - Sorbonne Université Bachelor's degree in Philosophy	Paris (FR)
2014-2017	IFSC - Instituto Federal de Santa Catarina Engineering Technician in Electronics	Florianópolis (BR)

## **Work Experience**

2020-2021	Student Researcher in Neural Nets at EMBRAPII, in partnership with Central Energia (R&E Worked on building, training, and evaluating LSTM neing the prediction of precipitation data for energy training.	etworks regard-
2018-2021	Student Researcher in Algebraic Topology at IMPA (Brazilian Institute of Pure and Applied Mathe Research on advanced topics related to Geometric Gr	,
2018–2019	Calculus Teaching Assistant at the Mathematics Department, UFSC Developed PHP, Shell, BASIC and Kernel scripts to a related to the management, monitoring and control of	
2016–2017	Intern as Web Developer at Oi S.A. (third largest telecommunication company in Developed PHP, Shell, BASIC and Kernel scripts to a related to the management, monitoring and control of	automate tasks

## **Projects**

2022	Training Neural Networks with Kalman Filters Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Implementation of modern control methods for training Neural Nets and use of the Kalman filter as an optimization algorithm
2022	Exploring portfolio optimization methods, with BNP Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Construction, Implementation and Evaluation of different portfolio allocation methods
2022	System for inform on cancer, with Health Guide AI Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Testing of different recommendation algorithms for this purpose
2021-2022	Neural Nets: Attacks and Robustness, with SystemX Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Study and implementation of some attack methods on NN systems

### **Honours and Awards**

2021	BRAFITEC, Merit Scholarship for Double Degree in France
2019	Qualified to Final Phase, OBMU (National University Maths Olympiad)
2018	Freshman Award, OEI (Organization of Ibero-American States)
2017	Silver Medal, OBMEP (National High School Mathematics Olympiad)
2016	Silver Medal, OBMEP (National High School Mathematics Olympiad)
2014	Honourable Mention, OBMEP (National High School Maths Olympiad)